Good to see you.
>> Hey, good to see you, man.
>> Uh, welcome to D program. I'm Ted R.
That's John Kuryaku. And it is Thursday,
September 4th. We're here, as promised,
5:00 PM Eastern time, as we are Monday
through Friday, every single weekday,
unless we're not. So, but normally we
are. Um, okay. So, today we've got a lot
to talk about, John. And obviously, as
usual, we're always responsive to your
questions and comments. Yes, indeed.
>> We love those. So, um, China big cyber
attack revealed last year. Salt typhoon
is the code word. Targeted over 80
countries, got into all the telephone
companies, stole data. Apparently,
according to uh the experts, from nearly
pretty much every single American
citizen. So, that's why the headline
today is China's got your number. Uh,
we'll talk a little bit about that. I I
was fascinated by this. Um, there's war
games models using AI models like GPT4
tend to escalate conflicts kind of like
in the movie war games back from the
80s. Why is that? Uh, we'll talk about
that. And uh there's a story out of the
Russo Ukrainian conflict where both
sides are using telegram which is very
popular in that part of the world to
basically recruit and exploit naive
teenagers, children really to ask them
to participate in sabotage operations,
usually not for patriotic reasons, but
for money. Um and they use blackmail and
deception to do so. Ruin their lives.
over 175 child uh dupes in from Ukraine
face charges for attempted lame
attempted sabotage in Russia. And
finally, we know courtesy of uh the New
York Post and others what exactly the
feds got out of John Bolton's house. So,
what first? What shall we talk?
>> What first? There's so much to say. I I
will add something about this uh
sabotage thing. Great. There was a piece
and I think it was in the New York
Times, I'm going to say three, four,
five months ago, saying that um that
there are other
um there are non-state actors like um
terrorist groups that are targeting
disaffected teenagers
on places like Discord or Twitch or
whatever and for 50 bucks, you know, or
a hundred bucks getting them to throw a
Molotov cocktail, put a small, you know,
explosive device in front of a store or
bank or whatever. This is this is a
thing now. It's not just the Russians
and the Ukrainians. Bad people are
convincing disaffected teenagers to do
bad things. And more often than not,
they get caught.
>> Yeah. Well, as you'd expect, because
they're hardly professionals. So, uh,
reading from the New York Times today,
this is how it works. First, an
anonymous user contacts kids over
Telegram, WhatsApp, or a video game chat
with an offer of some money. Once
contact is made, handlers provide
instructions. Sometimes the instructions
are disguised as a geoloccation game.
Uh, yes, we pay for photos here, says
one ad, asking for location stamped
pictures of police cars and ambulances.
This is a quote from the ad. It's like
Pokemon Go, but for money. Sometimes the
methods can be darker than deceit. A
14-year-old Ukrainian girl was harassed
by her Russian recruiters. They got
access to her intimate photos, then
threatened to post them online.
>> Exactly.
>> Became a sabotur.
>> And kids have committed suicide because
of that,
>> right? Aside from this kind of aside
from the war. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> It's it's it's rampant actually. I mean,
when this started, um, you know, my kid,
uh, was of that age. He was a, he was a
high school kid, and I had to sit down
with him and say, "Listen, if anything
like that ever happens, you have to
know, you know, I'll be there for you.
Don't be embarrassed." Like, you know, I
I I won't give a [__] except I'll want
to kill the people who are doing that to
you.
>> I'm not going to be upset with you.
Parents really need to to to talk to
their kids about this.
>> Amen to that. Yeah. This is this is
shame on both Russia and Ukraine for
doing something like this. Kids are so
easily exploited. Um their brains aren't
fully formed. They think that uh that a
couple of bucks like this is a lot of
money and they don't process the notion
that that they're probably going to get
caught. And if they're if they're
caught, it's going to cause no end of of
legal problems.
Yeah, this is a real shame.
>> I mean, okay. So, I mean, in the
interest of I mean, I think there's a
difference, but John, um, you know,
during World War II, resistance
organizations
>> in like, you know, Greece and France,
you know, our our our native lands,
they they used a lot of teenagers to do
Yeah.
>> conduct resistance activities and some
and a bunch of them were caught by the
Nazis and tortured and executed.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Is I mean, you know, I guess
the question that like the Russian and
Ukrainian intelligence services might
ask is how is this any different?
>> I mean, I think it's different.
>> I think it's different. You know, if
your survival is on the line, that's one
thing. Um,
>> and if you volunteer, right, I think I
think the
>> volunteer. I mean, I think the
difference is like I don't think the
French resistance or the Greek
resistance were running around basically
uh you know, blackmailing kids with nude
photos of themselves. They did not
>> to say like, "Hey, join fight the Nazis
or else." I mean, they were these were
patriotic young people who hated the
Germans and the invaders and they just
wanted to to kick them out no matter
what.
>> That's exactly right.
>> They were just patriots
>> as long as you go in with your eyes
open. You told this story yesterday
about your grandfather.
My grandmother did something similar and
was and was caught and imprisoned by um
by the quizzling government that was in
uh Athens at the time. My grandfather
bribed a prison guard with American
magazines to let her go and they escaped
to the United States. Um but
yeah, like I said, kids can't process
this kind of thing. They can't really
they can't really consider um consider
ideas of what might happen to them if
they get caught. And it's just I think
it's just very very dangerous. Very
dangerous.
>> Uh over on YouTube, Briel Definit says,
which is bal is a great word. It's fog.
Uh last last year, mostly Bulgarians
were caught in Paris doing pro-Russian
actions like smearing uh tags on on
monuments. all said that they were
recruited on Telegram.
>> Wow. You see you see there.
>> I mean, you know, at least that's just
that's just graffiti.
>> At least yes, there's that. It's not
planting a bomb in front of a police
station or or what have you.
>> No,
>> still.
>> So, um abuse.
>> No, it is I mean, you know, I mean,
maybe what we need is an international I
mean, I do think we need an
international convent. We have an
international convention against mines.
Not everybody adheres to it, but it
reduces the use of them enormously. The
US is one of the worst offenders because
we didn't sign that treaty.
>> That's right.
>> I think we need one against um drone
warfare. I don't know how you feel about
that.
>> Oh my god. Amen. And you know what's
what makes that even more important and
more immediate is the fact that drone
drone warfare is the future.
>> Oh yeah.
>> And it's going in terrible. Yeah. It's
the present there.
It's the present in Somalia,
>> you know. We've drone the [__] out of
people in Somalia. It doesn't even make
the papers,
>> you know, and I I interviewed Bernie
Sanders for my uh when I wrote that
biography of him and I asked him about
this and I was really surprised, you
know. I said, "How do you feel about he
said killing's killing? You know, who
cares if you use a drone or a or you
shoot the person in the head?" And I was
like, "The difference is that it's
frictionless. You don't even risk a
single one of your citizens to do this.
You just literally push a button and sit
in a trailer in Nevada and watch someone
blow up. And I think it's too easy.
>> And speaking of sitting in a trailer in
Nevada, I I hope that our viewers and
listeners know the name Daniel Hail. I
think Daniel Hail is is a a an
especially heroic whistleblower.
who went to prison for four and a half
years after blowing the whistle on the
drone program. He tells a terrible story
that that is worthy of repeating here.
He was in this trailer in Nevada on an
air base in Nevada operating like a
video game. The toggles for a drone
>> and the drone is over Afghanistan
and his boss is at McDilla Air Force
Base in Florida.
>> They're both looking at the screen.
>> They see they see the target and his
boss says, "Fire." And Daniel says, "I
can't fire. There are two little kids
with him." And his boss says, "Those
aren't kids. Those are goats." And he
said, "I'm telling you, I'm looking at
them and they're kids." And the guy
says, "Fire
or be uh court marshaled."
>> What the?
>> And so he fires and he killed a
9-year-old girl and a 12year-old girl.
And he said that he went home that night
and he told his roommate, "I became a
child killer today."
And that's when he decided to blow the
whistle. And of course, what happened to
him? He's arrested. He's charged with
multiple counts of espionage. And um
>> what a joke.
>> Goes through the whole process. He was
extraordinarily brave by refusing to
take a plea deal and he went to trial. I
happened to be at his sentencing. And I
went with Tom Drake. And um Daniel Hail,
you know, Daniel, if you if you ask
Daniel about it, Daniel will say, "Oh,
I'm I'm weak. I'm soft. I buckled. I'm
this. I'm that." This guy is a hero.
Bona American hero who sacrificed
literally everything in his life so that
the American people could have the truth
about the drone program.
I said to him afterwards, he he was
suicidal and I said to him, "It's not as
bad as you think it is." I said, "You're
going to get 15% off for good behavior.
You're going to get 6 to 12 months home
confinement. And if you tell them that
you're an alcoholic or a drug addict,
they'll put you in something called
ARDAP, the residential drug and alcohol
program and you get 12 months off your
sentence if you just go to the classes.
So he got out of prison, I don't know,
year, year and a half ago. He was on
Twitter for a minute and I was like, "Oh
my god, Daniel Hail, welcome home.
American hero Daniel Hail." A week
later, he had shut down his Twitter
account and he's disappeared.
And all of my friends are like, "Have
you heard from Daniel?"
No, nobody's heard from Daniel. I don't
know what happened to him, but anyway, a
long way of saying
if you kill people by drone,
it's the same as walking up to them and
shooting them in the head. It doesn't
make it easier,
>> you know. And in fact, um,
>> might make it worse. Yeah, rebellious
rainbow unicorn says shooting other
people in in others in person risks
PTSD. Some thinks that's why the Nazis
made gas chambers. Too many Nazis went
nuts from killing people in person. And
that's true. They did have problems with
uh Germans uh lo kind of losing their
minds when they were shooting people in
those pits in Poland and uh in Western
Russia. But they also and they, you
know, they tried to get them drunk on
schnaps and and they tried to do that. I
think, you know, I I think they came up
with the gas chambers. It's just because
it was they're German. It was more
efficient. They wanted bigger numbers.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> They I don't
>> But I don't But Go ahead.
>> Yeah. Go ahead. Sorry. No, I mean I just
think that the problem the problem with
drone warfare is even if you accept the
idea that we should be assassinating
people on the other side of the world,
which I don't. But let's just say that
you accept that. At least if you send a
sniper or someone out there to get an
eye, you know, draw an eye. The story
you told, John, it illustrates the
point. There's no way that a pilot at
10,000 feet, no matter how high
resolution their their lens is, or a
drone, no matter how, you know, even if
it can read read the the date on a penny
on the ground, there's no way it can see
what's going on. It's just too far away.
The angle's not right. And drones [__]
up over and over. There was some study
>> during the uh the wars in Was you know
like well you when you were at the
agency uh you know after 9/11
>> the drone attacks in Wazeristan and it's
hard to get good numbers but the the the
guesstimate was that 50 uh out of
basically 49 out of 50 victims of drone
attacks in uh western Pakistan were
innocent victims and uh you know either
they were misargeted or they were just
like in the wrong place at the wrong
time when the drone drone blew the
Hellfire missile blew up someone else.
Ted, I had coffee an hour ago with a
British human rights um attorney uh
Clive Smith and he is representing Afia
Sadiki, which is a different story, but
we had this same conversation, the same
exact conversation that you're talking
about right now where I well I said to
him when he when he raised the issue of
of using drones in Afghanistan, I said,
"You don't have any idea A how many
how many weddings we droned
just because
there was a tall guy wearing white.
>> Yes.
>> Right. I mean that was that was
>> or a black or a black turban under the
doctrine that tal Talibes always wore
black turbans did a lot of other people
>> and and then we would have to you know
send a million dollars and and ask the
government to you know spread the
million around to the family and then we
would do it again and again and again
and again and sometimes
we would blow up a a wedding on purpose
because there was some senior Tylib
there and then we would blow up his
funeral and kill everybody that went to
the funeral.
>> Right.
>> Well, listen,
>> the double tap strike,
>> 99%
plus of those people were just innocent
civilians, you know, local villagers,
relatives, you know, whatever. If if I
had a relative
If I had a relative who, let's say, was
involved in crime or whatever, okay,
he's a he's a relative of mine and he
dies, I'm going to go to his funeral.
Does that mean I deserve to be blown up,
too? Of course not.
>> No, it's outrageous.
>> No, it's absurd.
>> Uh, hey, John. Question for you from
Gasimos Katz. Uh, off topic, but can you
give Greeks your honest opinion on
Kimberly Gilfoil as US ambassador to
Greece?
>> See, now you put me on the spot there.
Uh, yes, I'll give you. But first,
before before these comments uh pass us,
I want to say thank you VM very much.
Thank you Sodon. Thank you Angela. And
thank you Marble. Honest to God, we we
couldn't do this without you. So, thank
you very very much.
>> So true.
>> And we're going to come back to your
questions in a second.
>> Yeah, we will.
>> Uh Kimberly Gilfoil.
>> I don't even know what to say.
>> You know what? You could just say pass.
>> No, I want to be honest.
I I have never been a Kimberly Gilfoil
fan. And And the reason why she got an
ambassadorship, any ambassadorship, is
because Donald Trump Jr. broke up with
her and they didn't want her around to
cause trouble in his next relationship.
It's the sad truth and so they decided,
ah, we'll we'll give her a an
ambassadorship and she'll be out for the
next three years, right?
>> Sure.
>> This is Saddam Hussein used to do this.
If there was anybody that was
particularly popular, especially if they
were a military officer, if you became a
general and you were you made some real
wins on the battlefield against the
Iranians, Saddam's going to be afraid of
you that you're going to try to
overthrow him and make yourself
president. So, he made you ambassador to
the Philippines,
>> right? Send get you out of the way. I
mean, it's what the military does. Like
my my, you know, my father was in the
Air Force. He would say like, "Oh, they
just if you're a pain in the ass, they
just promote you to the other side of
the world or the other side of the
country."
>> Exactly. So, they they gave Kimberly
Gilfoil this job just to get her out.
Now, it just happened to be in Greece.
Okay. And as a Greek American, as a
Greek, I'm a Greek citizen, I thought,
"Oh, this this is not going to be good
there. This is not going to be good."
Um, Greece has had a a long string of of
popular ambassadors
going back to and not including Nicholas
Burns, but everybody who came after Nick
Burns, everybody hate even those of us
who worked for Nick Burns hated Nick
Burns, but there have been a lot of
really good American ambassadors. George
Tunis, a very important Greek American
businessman being the most recent. I
mean, it's a pretty sweet assignment in
terms of
Athens.
>> Oh, yeah.
And the ambassador's residence is
magnificent.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I've watched Kimberly Gilfoil very
closely as she has gone through the
process, not just her Senate hearings,
although I watched those as well. I
watched every interview that she has
given. And I got to give her credit. She
has tried so hard to come down
positively in the eyes of the Greeks.
She has said all the right things. And
you know people like I I subscribe to um
to Kathyini the the daily newspaper and
also to ethnic the the English version
of ethnicoskidas. It's a national
herald. It's the the big English
language Greek American newspaper. And
you know, people are [__] all over
her. This is a terrible appointment. She
only got it because she was close to
Trump. But the truth is that that she's
an attorney. She's a former um assistant
US attorney. She does have the ear of
the president whether she's in the inner
circle or not anymore. And she's not.
But she's not an idiot. Um she's also
very much a political animal. You
remember before she started dating uh uh
Donald Trump Jr., she was with
Nuome.
>> She was married to
>> She was married to to Gavin Newsome.
>> So weird.
>> She had too much work done. And I think
that's a big part of the problem.
>> I agree with you. But she she's not
stupid. She's very politically savvy.
It's only going to be three years. We
could have done worse. We could have had
Nick Burns come back, god forbid. And um
you know there just as an aside there
used to be there may be still still be a
newspaper called Pondiki which means
little mouse right and it was a it was a
a left-wing um satirical newspaper.
>> I love those. Oh like like in French
>> exactly right. In fact they might be
like sister papers.
>> Okay. So, they had a photoshopped
picture once of of a nude Ambassador
Burns on his hands and knees
>> with a dog collar on.
>> How come I don't get to work for
publications like
>> I know, right?
>> If I ever get if I ever run into exile
to France, I'm going straight to Lana.
And
>> well, and the and the minister of
education, Vaso Papandreo, who I never
liked. I never could stand her. She has
a whip and she's beating him in the on
his naked butt uh with a with a whip
while she's got him by the dog collar.
He was so angry
he lodged an official protest. It's like
dude, it's a satirical newspaper and
what you never heard of freedom of
speech and freedom of the press. So we
all went out and bought these
newspapers. It was the It was the back
cover of the paper that day and all of
us taped them up in front of our desks.
He didn't have access to the station
because he was the ambassador. He's not
a station employee. So, he never saw it.
But, and I'm not confirming or denying
the existence of a station in Athens.
I'm just saying, of course,
>> that's where I that's where I put up my
my thing. So, anyway, I think this could
be
>> we've got some questions to answer here
from people who have kindly paid VM.
Thank you so much for the 50 heroes.
Appreciate it. Avid fan, don't miss a
day.
>> We um like our thoughts on Belgian Well,
this will be your thoughts on Belgian
intelligence at some point if you have
any.
>> Yeah. You know what?
>> I won't make any jokes about how Belgian
intelligence is an oxymoron, but
>> I do have to tell you a Belgian story.
It's not about intelligence, but you'll
it just reminds me of this. Some You
know, I love stories about incredibly
stupid people. Um my ex-wife and I were
on a bullet train from Paris to um
Amsterdam and it goes through Brussels.
It goes through the Netherlands and
these two like douchebag like sort of
bros like 22 23 years old get on with
big duffles and uh and they leave them
in the in the middle of the aisle where
people are trying to walk. The several
times the conductor comes by and tells
them to uh you know in in in Flemish or
whatever like get that [__] out of the
out of there. Um, and each time, uh,
they, you know, they they they they pull
them out and then as soon as the guy's
gone, they put them back into the aisle.
This happens a number of times and, you
know, the guy's getting the the
conductors getting more and more angry.
Finally, he's had enough. The the train
stops and some policemen come on with
with the uh with the um conductor. He
points it to the two guys. The the cops
confront them. They open the bags and
they're full of weapons.
Full of guns. Big guns. And I'm like,
I'm like, come on.
>> And I'm like, you you couldn't keep them
on your lap. They were They're gun like
put them on your lap. They're gun
They're like douchy gun runners. I was
like, [__] Belgians. Anyway, what do
you think about Belgian intelligence?
>> This is one of those it's a small world
stories. So, when I was a senior in high
school, um we had a foreign exchange
student from Brussels, Pete Jambone.
And Pete and I are still like close
buddies. Uh he comes back to the States
just about every year and we're all like
in each other's weddings and we're
godfathers to each other's kids. Pete
and and my three other closest friends.
Um, Pete went into private business,
became very wealthy. His brother went
into government and became the director
of the Belgian intelligence service.
>> So, the last time he was here in the
States, we met up in Atlanta to go to
another one of our best friends son's
wedding. And um, I said, "So, how's your
brother doing in uh, in this intel
director slot?" And he said, "Oh, they
made him intel director and deputy prime
minister. It's the craziest thing." I
said, "Oh my god, well, how's he how's
he fitting in with intelligence?" And he
said, "You know, I never I never
realized that my brother had a hatred
for Arabs." And I'm like, "What?
You guys don't hate anybody."
And he says, "So every time I call him
on it," he said, "Oh, you don't see what
I see. If you could see what I see, I
said, "Oh, Pete, I hear that all the
time." Well, if you had access to what I
have access to, you'd want to kill
everybody. Well, no. I I used to have
access to what you had access to and I
never wanted to kill anybody. But um but
the Belgians are very good when it comes
to Arabs
>> and they pretty much ignore everything
else. It's all about the Arabs.
>> Huh. They're panicked at the idea that
that the Palestinian refugees, for
example, there are a lot of Palestinian
refugees in in Belgium
>> might be terrorist.
>> Yeah. Right. They might be terrorists.
They might
>> You remember France had that spate of
PLO bombings uh and other like Islamic
jihad bombings in Absolutely. Like they
got rid of all the trash cans and
mailboxes.
>> Yeah. Just like we did.
>> Did Belgium have the same issue?
>> Yes. Oh, yeah. Reed makes a great point.
I totally forgot about that. Fa season 4
was filmed in Belg in Belgium. That's
exactly right. It was.
>> And and then Reed remembered this too.
She also is asking I'm assume she's a
she. Wasn't Gilfoil accused of sexually
harassing a male intern when she worked
at Fox? I seem to remember that.
>> I think I do too.
>> Yeah,
>> I think I do too. I don't remember what
the what the final result was, but yeah,
I do remember that.
>> Yeah,
>> saucy.
>> Hell yeah.
>> Spicy. Uh, okay. So then, all right,
Sodom, thanks for the 20 bucks. Hey,
John and Ted, can you
>> can you please give us some insight as
to why the Brits allowed China to build
its huge embassy near the financial
district and has sublevel fiber optics?
Should the UK and the US be concerned?
It's a huge complex.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, you you know the story
about the American embassy in Moscow and
the Russian embassy in Washington. They
were both built around the same time.
The the deal was struck in the 1970s
that both uh countries would build new
embassies. And so we told the Russians,
go ahead and find a plot and a plot of
land and go ahead and pick what you
want. So they went to literally the
highest point in Washington.
>> See, I wonder why they they just wanted
to get channel 2 and channel 7 good
reception.
>> Yeah. And oh, by the way, you can also
see the White House and the Pentagon
from up there
>> and signals intelligence, right? Like
>> and signals intelligence is wonderful.
The Russians
allowed us to purchase a dry riverbed in
Moscow that was actually in this in this
culvert in the middle of Russia. And we
ended up having to tear the new embassy
down because the Russians had put
listening devices in literally every
beam and every 2x4 in the entire
embassy. Just pulling the wires out of
it would have made the building
collapse. So we would not allow them to
occupy their new embassy, which is way
up at the top of Wisconsin Avenue, just
immediately south of the National
Cathedral. You could see the Russian
embassy from everywhere in Washington.
It's
>> I love these I love these shenanigans
though. Um I had a college girlfriend.
She was a diplomatic brat and she was
she she grew up um at the um she spent
quite a few years at the American
embassy in Moscow uh during the I guess
this would have been in the 70s ' 80s
and she said that there were always
shenanigans like all of the staff all
the cleaning people they were all KGB no
question about it constantly there were
fires all the time and so it would be
like there's a fire everyone has to
leave the and you knew the firefighters
were all KGB and they were all going in
there and planting bugs. Everything had
to be swept over and over and over. They
knew they weren't catching them all. Um
and they also were really concerned
about cancer, right? Because
>> Oh, yeah. They were beaming They were
beaming microwaves at the embassy and
people were all getting cancer
>> because when you Yeah. Because what you
correct me if I'm wrong, my
understanding is if you talk inside a
room then the vi you can pick up the
vibration off the glass in the window.
>> Off the glass of the windows. Exactly.
Right. And so the microwaves like allow
you to hear what's going on inside.
>> You know, Ted, when I was living in
Bahrain, Bahrain, which is like joined
at the hip with the United States, uh,
defense and foreign policy wise, I was
the human rights officer in Bahrain. One
night I'm laying in bed with my wife and
I'm reading a book and it was really,
really hot. I had no shirt on. So I'm
reading a book and this thing falls onto
my chest. I'm like, "What the [__] is
this?" So, I look up.
The the air conditioning vent is
directly above me. I I pick this thing
up. It's clearly a bug.
It has wires sticking out of it. There's
a little battery, a little watch battery
on it.
>> So, I put it in a Ziploc bag. And the
next day I took it into the embassy
and uh and I took it to my chief
and he looks at it. He's holding it up.
He goes, "Yep, it's a bug." All right.
And I said, "Well, now what am I
supposed to do?" I said, "My wife almost
never leaves the house, but she must
have gone grocery shopping or something
or took our son to the park or
whatever." And they immediately went in
and planted this bug in the bedroom, no
less. In the bedroom.
>> That's Yeah, that's bad.
>> And And my wife was a ballet teacher.
She wasn't a She wasn't a CIA officer. I
would never ever discuss anything with
her because she wasn't cleared.
>> Sure.
>> And he said, "It's cuz you're writing
that damn human rights report." He said,
"They don't like you one bit." And then
I'll tell you what the Bahinis used to
do is whenever your tour was up,
you know, we're not allowed to accept
any gift worth more than $25.
So whenever your tour was up, they would
send everybody a Rolex and then you had
to report it to the Treasury Department
and you could either
um just turn it over or you could turn
it over and bid on it and buy it back
from the Treasury Department. Hm.
>> I was the only one in the entire embassy
that didn't get a Rolex when I left. I
didn't even get a, you know, thank you.
Come again. Nothing.
>> They hated you.
>> They hated me.
>> Well, we're all judged by
>> I would go into our enemies.
>> Oh my god. And I would go into the
Minister of Interior's office and I'd
say, "Your highness, you cannot just
pick up a 15-year-old kid off the street
for marching in a pro-democracy
demonstration, beat him to death, and
then call his parents to come and pick
up the body. You can't do that. I have
to report that to Congress, and it's
going to jeopardize the sale of uh of
weapons to Bahrain."
I said, "Back off."
>> Angela, thanks for the donation. Marble,
I love this question. Can someone please
explain how w how Laura Loomer is so
influential? Hey, uh if
>> what a mystery.
>> Yeah, seriously. Um
>> I don't know if someone has the answer.
I I honestly don't know.
>> Listen, Laura Loomer,
we have a mutual friend and I said I
said to the mutual friend, I said, "Why
do you even associate with somebody like
Laura Loomer? First of all, she's the
only person I've ever heard of that's
banned by Uber, by Lyft, and by Target
for for hate speech.
Seriously,
>> she's going to charge.
>> No, she can't go. She's not welcome
there. She's not welcome there. And I I
was like, how can you be friends with
somebody like that? Oh, no. She's
misunderstood. No, she's very well
understood. That's the issue here. So,
she ran for Congress
in it was either 202
or 2020, I can't remember, in Donald
Trump's home district of Palm Beach and
she got 24%. So even Republicans realize
that she is nuts and she is so far to
the right as to be unhinged,
but she has this inexplicable
influence over the president of the
United States. I don't understand it.
>> Yeah. I mean, maybe she made some
appearance on Fox that impressed him one
time or could
>> something like that. It's often like
that. Um, John Star Lion's asking,
>> "Yeah,
>> I thought you were really connected with
Bahraini royalty."
>> So, is that true?
>> Why, if that's true, why would the
security service still treat you like
crap?
>> The crown prince and I still still like
text each other jokes and stuff.
>> I just heard from him on Saturday, as a
matter of fact, but when I was in
Bahrain,
the director of the Bahraini
Intelligence Service was named General
Ian Henderson.
General Ian Henderson, who was the
British colonialist who put down the Mao
Rebellion
>> in Rhdesia. Yeah.
>> And did everything he could to keep
black Rhodesians
out of power
until he just had to flee and couldn't,
you know, hold them off anymore. went to
Bahrain and they said, "Hey, can you set
up an intelligence service for us?"
>> So Ian Anderson,
he was he was the worst kind of colonial
Brit to the point where even the Bahinis
were afraid of him. And I'll tell you
another thing, George HW Bush came to
Bahrain when I was there and the Amir
had a gigantic dinner for him. So the
crown prince asked that I be seated at
his table. So we're sitting there, we're
laughing. I was young at the time. I was
I was how old was I when I went to
Bahrain? I was 29.
And um so we're laughing and joking and
I said I said, "Who's the corpse over
here at this other table?" And he turns
and he says, "Seriously?" And I said,
"Yeah, it's like this 80-year-old man
literally wearing a brown leisure suit,
right, with the the loud flower shirt
underneath and the big wide collar with
the wide lapels from the 70s." I said,
"Yeah." I said, "Who's the stiff
And he says, "That's that's General
Henderson." And I go, "That's Ian
Henderson."
I said, "He looks like he crawled right
out of the 70s." He's like, "Yeah, you
know what? We we don't talk about
General Henderson." So even this is a
guy who who is at the time he was the
air presumptive because his grandfather
was the Amir and his father was the
crown prince. Now he's the crown prince.
But even the air presumptive
was afraid of Ian Henderson to the point
where he didn't even want to speak the
man's name.
>> Wow.
>> Love that.
>> Well, I I'm dying to get your thoughts
about this uh war games thing. So, um
there's this uh article that came out in
Politico about the a AI doomsday
machine. Basically the argument is that
uh you have to have autonomous warfare
self autonomous weapons in other words
weapons that choose their own targets
using AI are the future there's no way
to ignore it got to do it if we don't do
it the Chinese will do it the Russians
will do it we have to we have to keep up
DARPA is of course the big research arm
of the Pentagon they're keeping up so
anyway uh the problem that they're that
they're finding
is that chat GBT and other AI models uh
tend when fa when faced with a dilemma,
a military dilemma or situation or a
crisis, they tend to escalate rather
than deescalate. And so obviously, you
know, you don't have to have seen the
Terminator a million times like I have
to know how this works out. I have a
theory as to why this is true, John, but
I want to hear yours first.
>> You want to hear mine first, Ted? This
is Black Mirror come to life.
>> Mhm.
>> It really is uh the future. I hate to
say it and it scares the hell out of me.
Um you know those robot dogs, that
episode of Black Mirror where the robot
those are real and they even look like
that.
>> Yeah, they look dogs.
Once DARPA can perfect a battery that
has a a long enough life that we can
attach it to a robot to go fight our
wars,
everything changes because we're very
quickly getting to a point where the
ultimate goal is to not send human
beings into battle. on our side. It's to
send robots, robot dogs, drones, all
powered by AI
to fight our wars, you know, without
having to spend
or to ex expend a single life. Let me
add one thing. Many of you know that I'm
a a huge fan of really bad 60s and 70s
television. I just I'm addicted to it.
Right now, I've got over here Dragnet uh
in my queue. I have Dragnet, Adam 12,
and Star Trek.
>> 12, one, Adam 12,
>> only the original Star Trek. Well, there
is a Star Trek episode that is apppropo
of this conversation.
They go to this planet. Kirk and Spock
go to this planet and uh they hate the
people on the next planet, right? These
planets are really close together. They
hate these people on this next planet.
So, one of them calls and says the one
planet called planet A calls planet B
and they said, "Okay, listen. We're
launching an attack on you guys." So,
uh, here it comes.
[Music]
Okay, it impacted at such and such a
coordinate. And then planet B says, "Oh
crap. Okay, you killed 3,500 people."
But they didn't really. what they were
doing was these computer games, computer
exercises. So then if the computer says,
"Well, yeah, that that was a direct hit.
It killed 35 people." They would send 35
people to these death chambers to be to
be put to death. But that way
you didn't have to keep rebuilding all
the buildings.
>> Mhm. And then they would launch a
counteratt attack and oh we killed
10,000 people in the counterattack so
now you have to send 10,000 people.
>> It's a simulation basically. We really
do kill the people after the fact. This
crazy thing is that's history.
>> Well in ancient history I don't remember
if it's the Assyrians or the Hittites or
both but they they kind of got to the
point where they were tired of
destroying each other's cities. And so
this they would do this a similar thing
where they would line up the armies um
side by side and then basically the
equivalent of a military CPA would count
all the men and all the weapons and
assess their training and they would
negotiate and they'd say, "Okay, in this
battle um the Hittites would have won.
So therefore you we're nobody's going to
kill anyone. we're all going to go home
to our wives and kids, but we're going
to um seed this amount of territory or
this amount of money or whatever. Uh and
that's how they used to do it. And it
sounds civilized, I guess. But so, John,
here's my theory. I I'm really dying to
hear what you think. So, my theory is
chat GPT, Grock, all these uh Google AI,
they're all trained by illegally
scraping everything they can from the
internet. Basically, they have spiders
and bots everywhere. And so, they're
getting basically the entire internet.
Well, what's the internet? It's the
expression of our political and other
culture. And our culture is always
escalatory, whether it's in war or
whether it's in culture, you know? I
mean, just think about like even in
relationships if someone's like, "Oh,
like my husband forgot my anniversary.
Oh, divorce. [__] him. divorce him.
Everything is always like goes to 11.
Our culture, I mean, think about when
there's a military, a foreign crisis.
When's the last time you watched CNN or
MSNBC and there was one single member of
the panel who said, you know, maybe the
US shouldn't be involved. It's not
really our business. Or we should try to
negotiate peace. We should we should go
and and and like we really need to be
peace. I've ne I'm 62 years old and I
have never wa in watching tens of
thousands of hours of cable to news
television ever heard a single person
who said this is not our business or
really we should try to be we should
deescalate this situation. So I think
the what's all that's happening is that
the is that the bots are trained on an
escalatory culture. So of course they
[__] escalate everything.
>> Of course they do. And why is it that
we've not yet been able to put together
intellectually the fact that they are
automatically escalatory
and they are convincing teenagers to
kill themselves.
>> And number three, that's a problem. And
then taken in combination, it's going to
be a very big problem.
>> I say all the time, and I say it only
half jokingly, Ted,
>> I saw iRoot. I saw what happened when
the blue light turns red and I'm not
looking forward to it.
>> No, it's not.
>> And you know that that's where we're
headed.
>> And that's the thing is, right, we we
put every I mean, you wonder why we have
so much mental illness in our society,
right? I mean, we pour on the pressure.
Just think about every single day, even
if you're doing everything right, you
know, you'll get that notice like, oh,
you know, disconnection notice if you
don't send in your, you know, your
payment right away, we're going to turn
off your power. instead of like, "Hey,
by the way, you're running a little
late, dude. Like, don't forget to send
in your they that's never how it is,
right? Everything is like in America,
you know, you're a hammer. Everything
looks like a nail." That's that's what
it is. And the people who run the
country are no different.
>> That is absolutely right.
>> So, all right. Well, I'm glad you like
my theory.
>> I was pretty proud of it. And I was
like, I'm with you.
>> I was like, I think I I think I've got
this. Um, let's talk about your good
friend, the walrus. I am the walrus. I
am the empire.
>> Yeah, the walrus.
>> Mr. Bolton. Yeah.
>> Um, so he got raided a couple weeks ago,
August 22nd. Um, and now we kind of know
what it was all about. They grabbed the
feds grabbed three computers, two
iPhones, bunch of old documents. Turns
out that he apparently was sending a lot
of classified information to family
members. Um and um and that's where what
this investigation is about. Uh he's
basically uh I think he's in trouble,
right? I mean I mean it sounds like he
legitimately did some illegal stuff.
>> That is literally the definition of
espionage in the Espionage Act. Remember
the definition of espionage was kind of
mainstreamed in my case. It set a
precedent. It is providing national
defense information to any person not
entitled to receive it. There it is. And
I'm looking here. Uh, the feds raided
Bolton's Bethesda home in Washington DC
office as part of an investigation into
allegations that he snuck national
security files out of the White House
during President Trump's first term by
emailing them to family members on a
private server. And that's all according
to the FBI.
>> By the way, is is John Bolton stupid? I
mean, I know he's not like very smart
when it comes to foreign policy.
>> Arrogant. He's arrogant is what it is.
This is arrogance. Edward Snowden used
thumb drives, right?
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> It's also a lot faster.
>> I mean I mean you can find out, right?
You you can learn if if data has been
taken that way, but it just seems But if
you're doing it by email, I mean it's
going to go through a server. It's going
to be known, right? Isn't I mean that
goes through a server that
>> that is monitored. I mean it's
impossible that it won't be known and
known soon.
>> Well, there the FBI is saying this too.
in addition to um
to taking all of his electronics, they
took everything, which they normally do.
Um in fact, on the back of my computer
that I'm talking to you through, I still
have an FBI sticker on the back that
says evidence on it that at first I
couldn't get it off and now I just I
keep it just as a souvenir.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I thought so, too. But it
says the FBI also confiscated two USB
drives, a hard drive, four boxes marked
printed daily activities,
typed documents in folders labeled Trump
1 through 4, and a white binder labeled
statements and reflections to Allied
strikes. Uh, and it goes on to say that
the warrant specifically accuses him of
violating two different sections of the
Espionage Act. So yeah, this is real.
He's in real trouble.
>> So you think he's just you think he took
the Do you think he sent the stuff to
his family to brag or just to get it
just to get it to himself and thought
that he wouldn't get caught? He was This
is for his memoir is what I I would
>> Exactly. Exactly. This is for his
memoir. And I think he probably did it
just to make it easier for him to access
later. I I don't think he listen.
>> By the way, if I were gonna do this, and
I this is not advice to anyone, but if I
were going to do this, I would take
screenshots with my phone of the of my
computer screen, right? And that's just
what I would do. And then I could toss
the phone later.
>> Although Although that's how they caught
uh Oh, the FBI whistleblower from
Minneapolis. His name escapes me.
>> Yeah. But couldn't you?
>> That's exactly.
>> But I mean you But if you let's just say
the phone's not attached to the
internet, you can turn it off, right?
>> Yeah.
>> You just have You just use us as a
camera. I mean, hell, just bring a
camera.
>> Bring a camera. Yes.
>> I mean, old school like the little
>> See, but but this is that arrogance that
we would expect from somebody like John
Bolton.
>> Also, he's old
the internet that well.
>> Yeah, he's actually and he's not looking
good at all. He looks
really worn out. Yeah, he does look he
does not look the same. Um, I guess you
probably have some sense of what that's
like when you go when you go through
something like that. Star Lion's asking
if you ever got a chance to to work with
John Perry Barlo, co-founder of the EFF,
the Electronic Frontier Foundation.
>> No, I've spoken to him a couple of
times, but I never had a chance to to
work with him.
Um, you know, I've been told for that
for whatever reason I'm not the most
popular person at the EFF. I don't know
why because I always liked and respected
them, but I
>> you know what that's that's how it was
for me. I found out the same thing about
me. I had every first amendment
organization in the United States on my
side um sending amicus briefs against
the LA Times, which is saying something
because they're a newspaper and normally
they, you know, they would be on their
side. But what but the two big
exceptions were the EFF um who said, you
know, you're not popular here and uh the
ACLU of Southern California
>> totally because they had a deal with the
LA Times, but the ACLU national would
have been on my side, but the ACLU makes
their decisions regionally. So, a member
of the board of the ACLU resigned in
protest of the ACLU not making a
statement in support of me during my
trial.
And um
I got a letter.
>> They're [__]
>> Oh, tell me about it. Not as big a bunch
of [__] as uh Amnesty International
is.
>> So Amnesty International
>> refused
to say a single word in support of me in
my darkest days of 2012.
This this was Amnesty International
London, the the headquarters. So, the
head of of Amnesty International United
States, a guy named Zeke, uh I think his
last name was Johnson. Awesome guy. He
wrote me a letter when I was in prison
apologizing
for his bosses in London. And then he
bought me a subscription to The New
Yorker to kind of, you know, dull the
pain, I guess. But it was only later
when I was getting out of prison
that Iwei Weii, the Chinese uh artist,
he wanted to do my portrait for this
show at uh at Alcatraz. He he he made
178 portraits out of Legos of 178
political prisoners around the world.
And so he wanted to clear the names with
Amnesty International first. And Amnesty
said, "Oh, we don't believe Kiryaku is a
political prisoner." and he said, "Oh, I
know Kiryaku. I'm telling you, he is a
political prisoner." And so they finally
agreed. And it was the week that I got
out of prison
that Amnesty International finally said,
"Okay, okay, you were a political
prisoner."
But they had to be, you know, pulled
kicking and screaming uh to to that
point of view. They were really
>> And sometimes it is like that. Yeah.
when you're when when you're fighting
for your life and you're making calls to
these groups and you know it's amazing.
You kind of think like I mean some of
them it was a mixed bag. I ended up with
eight amicus briefs. Um but like uh you
know some of them came through like just
great. Then others you know you're
literally like are you [__] serious?
You're really not going to side with me?
Really? Like you know what they did? And
they're like
>> yeah. And it's like but that's what
you're for. That's the purpose. That's
That's why you get donations. I mean,
including I used to donate to the ACLU.
They had a cartoon auction every year.
Always used to spend a cartoon. I'm
like, "Thanks a lot, [__] No more no
more cartoons from me."
>> Unbelievable, these people. And you
know, somebody told me the other day,
there's a very there's a very prominent
uh uh attorney here in uh
um here in Washington, very prominent.
And uh a mutual friend told me, "You
know, he doesn't think you're a
whistleblower." And I said, "But isn't
it wonderful to be at a point in my life
where I don't give a [__] what he thinks
about me?"
>> That is nice.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's Yeah. Yeah. No, I
mean, I went through Yeah. I mean, you
know, when you interview me, I'll get
into all the nuts and bolts of the uh By
the way, for people who are we're now on
we've now dropped uh we're dropping hour
three of the my interview with John uh
for Rumble Premium and it's great. We're
going to do probably two more hours and
then we'll do mine. But when we do mine,
it's like when you hear it like sort of,
you know, the way this all went down and
like it was kind of like but you kind of
have to believe me because it's been
proven.
>> Exactly. it was proven by science and
then it's like well I don't know like
it's like there were there were still
some people there's a I mean seriously
there's a there's a cartoonist who um
shall remain nameless except that he's
was the cartoonist at the Salt Lake City
paper for many many years and probably
still is um and he would and he was
telling my friend Scott Standis like I
don't know I think Ted faked that
evidence it's like why you think so you
think Ted has the power of like a major
like espionage agency to to fake to
break into the LAPD vault, alter their
evidence, and then use it to exonerate
himself. Like, if that if I had that
power, I wouldn't be here doing podcasts
and drawing cartoons,
>> you know? Absurd. But people believe
what they want to believe.
>> Oh my god.
>> Anyway, yeah, I know it's depressing,
but you know, it is nice to get to the
point where you just don't care. Uh, oh
yeah, let's talk about Reed, by the way.
Uh, Reed's a dude. My apologies. Um,
>> yeah.
>> Uh, Fel Federman going through a serious
mental health crisis. I mean, still.
>> Um, I guess it's getting worse. I can't
believe that guy is still in the Senate.
I mean, John, you're from Pennsylvania.
How do you feel about that? I think it's
a [__] I think it's atrocious.
>> It's a It's a travesty, and I'm furious
about it. Although, I'll tell you why
he's still in the Senate. because
he has maintained the strong support of
organized labor. He hasn't budged on his
support for organized labor and he has
become what Republicans are now calling
Donald Trump's favorite Democrat.
And in a state like Pennsylvania, which
goes, you know, back and forth and back
and forth between the two parties,
that's the position you want to be in.
So people like you and I have zero
respect for the guy.
>> No.
>> But they don't care what people like you
and I think. The union members are going
to vote for him and Republicans are
going to vote for him and that's why
he's able to do this. Now with that
said, that question that you just put up
on the screen, why is John Federman
still in the Senate? That's the
question. Because if he is mentally and
emotionally unable to serve
>> and apparently physically I mean he
literally doesn't show up to votes.
>> He doesn't talk and he doesn't uh
interact with constituents. His staff I
mean he can't keep any staff members
because he's crazy and his staff run
away. He's mean. He's mean. Yes.
>> I told you I saw him at that Ohio State
football game. He was like 10 rows in
front of me and I kept shouting,
"Fetterman, I want my 50 bucks back."
And so he could hear his name, but I
think because of the crowd, he he
couldn't really hear what I was saying.
So he would just turn around and go,
"H boy, I hate that guy."
>> No, I mean, he's he's such a dick. And I
mean, you know, the funny part though is
because he's he's become even more
maniacally pro-Zionist.
>> Oh, yeah. It's irrational.
>> And that's kind of like kind of
interesting, right? So maybe nowadays to
be Zionist, you literally have to be
insane.
>> Yes.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> So,
>> um, Matthew Blair Reigns has a good
question and thank you for the 10
pounds, Matthew. Why did or does the UK
and France have such different
approaches to their former
colonies/mpire
both with regards to military and
intelligence actions? That's a great
question. Um, I will say that the only
thing the French really care about is
they just don't want to be attacked by
people who used to be from who are from
what used to be colonies. So, they're
happy to go to to, you know, the Sahel
and and try to fight al-Qaeda, but
otherwise they're they're willing to
just get up and walk away.
>> I think the French Yeah. The French po
approach to postc colonialization has
been like if there's a fire we'll come
in with the French foreign legion and
put it out
>> and then we'll go home.
>> Exactly. And the Brits don't want to do
that.
>> But the Brits had the commonwealth.
>> Yeah. and and they so the the illusion
here is that technically speaking,
right, the king's face is still on the
money in Canada and Australia
and Bise and on the Bahamas and all over
the all these places that are ostensibly
independent.
>> They just Yeah. They the Brits have
trouble letting go. They want to think
that they're still a colonial power.
They think they want to still think that
they run an empire.
>> Yes. And I think that's part of the
Brexit mentality, ironically, even
though, you know, the people who voted
for it probably weren't thinking like
that at all. I think it's culture. Um,
>> you know, I I think it's like the French
I think the deal is like this. The
French think that they that they have
majesty because they're France and that
like they and that they bestowed some of
their majesty on their on their
colonies. I think the Brits think that
their majesty comes from having
colonies.
>> That's a good point. I could see that.
That actually makes sense to me. Hey,
big boss Bob Ross has a good question
here. Why did the French help the
genocidal Hoou government uh during the
Rwanda genocide? I never understood a
single aspect of that genocide.
You know, there are there were hoous and
and tootssis who were, you know, married
into each other's families.
>> Hoous living next door to tootssis for
generations and and then like flipping a
switch, they all started killing each
other. I I just didn't understand it.
Can you make heads or tails of this?
>> Yeah. I mean, it was a defi It was a It
was a classic divide and conquer
strategy. Um and basically, you know,
the whole idea that there's even such a
thing as hoous and tootssis. was
invented by the by the by the colonial
powers. Um and and it was like basically
it was a traditional approach to take a
favored minority you know group and make
put them in charge. Um you know kind of
like uh I guess you could sort of say
that was the model that the Brits
pursued in in uh you know in in the in
uh in Iraq and stuff like that. Um, so I
think I think it was like, you know,
support the minority. Uh, they will
fight hard to oppress the majority, but
the majority will be resentful and
seething and they'll fight each other.
You know, it's kind of like like Stalin
when he when he drew the the borders of
the Central Asian republics um
>> and he put uh like 40% of Usuzbekistan
was Taji, 40% of Tajikistan was Usuzbek.
>> Wow.
>> Um and it was like on purpose because he
thought the Forgana Valley Muslims were
crazy and would rebel against the the
Soviet Union. And he wasn't really wrong
about that.
>> Wow. Yeah, he wasn't really wrong about
that.
>> But um you know, I mean, I'm we're we
don't have all the times in the world
here to to teach a class on postc
colonialism, but u you know, I think
that's that's sort of the the short
version of that.
>> Um
what do we think of uh Ibraim? I don't
even know who this is. I tror
>> Oh, I know him. He's a young guy. He's a
young military officer in Burkina Faso
uh that took power I don't know two
three four years ago.
>> Yeah.
>> From the French.
>> Yeah. He well he overthrew the
government
>> and um and took power. He's he's become
in my view increasingly irrational over
the last couple of months. He first of
all he took power. It's been at least
three years now and there has been no
transition back to democracy which he
had promised at the outset. didn't
happen. He's He's the dictator. The
military dictator.
>> That's what they always do.
>> They always say that.
>> Well, we will have an election as soon
as things settle down.
>> Yeah, exactly. But just recently, he did
a couple he did a couple things um where
he outlawed homosexuality. So, if you're
gay, you risk 10 years in prison for
being gay. And the other thing he did
was um and I I read this I think it I
think I saw in the BBC where he did away
with the country's electoral commission.
The Bkina I don't even know why I know
this much about Bkina Faso but they have
this permanent electoral commission and
the job of the electoral commission is
to plan each election. So every four
years you have an election. It's you
know these people that run the election.
He scrapped it. Fired everybody. Got rid
of everybody. He took personal control.
Fire everyone.
>> Fire everyone. You take over
and um and there aren't going to be any
elections. And then also recently, I
don't remember where I saw this, but he
started to expel foreigners
like to expel it's a program now to
expel all of the foreigners from Burkina
Faso. It's I mean, Burkina Fasa was
never a a garden uh spot,
but um but man, it's getting worse and
worse and worse.
>> Military dictatorship always fun. Um
so, all right. So, do we want to talk
about Salt Typhoon or should we call it
a night?
>> Yeah, let's say something quickly about
Salt Typhoon. Um, the Chinese are really
good at uh at computer attacks. They're
just really good. And they've got this
unit within the Chinese intelligence
service that only does cyber warfare.
And they hit the jackpot with this
thing, this salt typhoon, where they
they hacked the information of literally
every American. Now, there are a couple
of outlets today and yesterday that were
saying that that the real targets of
this thing were Donald Trump and JD
Vance, but then they thought, "Ah, no,
we'll just cast a wide net and see how
much success we can have." And they had
complete success where they were able to
collect data from every single American.
They're good. and our defenses are not
so good.
>> So I guess at this point right I mean
every sing it seems like every few
months or weeks we wake up to you know
some data breach like oh every single
you know Target lost all of their credit
card data uh Master Card lost all of
your data. The dark web has everyone's
social security numbers. China has
everything. um you know you go and use a
password somewhere uh and there it'll
you'll be warned oh change your password
this password is exists on the dark web.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean I think most people I don't think
I'm alone just sort of just throw up
their hands and they're like [__] it.
It's like there's no way to safeguard my
data anyway. I I can't be bothered. You
know if people want to steal my identity
they can have it. Um it just seems like
it's there's no resources. There's
nothing really that it doesn't feel like
there's anything you can even do about
it. And John, I can't remember a single
politician even giving a speech one time
saying, "Hey, this is a major concern
and we are we probably ought to have
some committees and and talk about this
stuff and do something about it." It's
literally like it just happens in the
paper and you read it and you're like,
"Oh, okay." And there's no leadership
whatsoever.
>> Yeah, you're absolutely right. and
Marble. Thanks again, Marble. Marble's
got one other question. Uh John and Ted,
why did Russia recognize the Taliban
government? I've got a theory.
>> Um the theory is they did it for a
couple of reasons. One, to put
Afghanistan finally behind them. Okay,
that's nice. The real reason
because the United States hasn't. And
this is yet another opportunity for
Russia or China for that matter to move
in where the US has been too reluctant.
Maybe negotiate a nice sweetheart deal
on rare earth metals or on whatever
establishing new trade relations,
whatever.
>> Uh we should have recognized the Taliban
immediately.
>> Couldn't hurt with bricks. I mean, if
you're going to have
>> Absolutely right. you want a good
relationship, you know, if you want
trade relations between Russia and
India, it's the Silk Road.
>> Yep.
>> You know,
>> that's right.
>> The Taliban, one thing that they are
able, they're very, very good at is
providing security on the ground. Y
>> and uh you know, trucks can make it
across and make it into Usbekistsan or
Turk Manosan and then onto Russia.
>> Yes.
>> No problem. And vice versa.
>> Yes, indeed. That's right.
>> Pipelines, oilines. Exactly. You know, I
wrote an entire book about the Trans
Afghanistan pipeline project that Bill
Clinton uh and Unical tried to start in
the mid 90s and uh you know that could
be revived now.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> I mean, the problem was that you could
never run a pipeline across such a
rustive place, you know, where tribesmen
would be constantly threatening to blow
it up.
>> That's right.
>> I think it's a good I think it's a good
thing. I think honestly I think every
honestly I got to tell you I don't think
diplomatic uh recognition you tell me
what you think. I don't even think it
should be like one of those things that
is like a reward or something.
>> Totally agree.
>> You should just every diplomatic
relations with every other country.
Period.
>> Let the diplomats do what they're paid
to do to carry out diplomacy. We should
have relations with everybody. We really
should. Everybody that wants relations
with us. I mean because the truth is
when we need to talk to people you know
we end up talking to them anyway. Um
right when I needed a visa to go to Iran
we don't have diplomatic relations but
they had a Iran had an interest section
in the Pakistani embassy in in
Washington and that's what my fixer went
through to get it. Um and it's like so
in other words you know the US has to
talk to Iran sometimes they have to but
this just make the lack of diplomatic
relations just makes it harder for them
to do their jobs. That's right. That's
right. I'm proud to say, I've not said
this publicly, but I'm going to say it
now. I'm one of six people
um who has been invited to meet with
Iranian President Peshkian in New York
when he arrives for the UN General
Assembly. And I said I said yes. I
>> didn't even ask what he wanted to talk
about. So, um
>> that's great.
>> I'm I'm excited about it. Um
>> do an interview.
Why not? The worst that could happen is
that he says no,
>> right?
>> Yeah, why not?
>> Yeah, be great. Invite, please invite
him.
>> It's going to be exciting. Um I I heard
back from them again today. They said
that they don't yet have a date or a
time, but there are six of us that he
wants to talk to.
Uh Medadia Benjamin is one. Uh Max
Blumenthal is one. Andy Shal is one. Me
and I don't know who the other two are.
>> That's awesome.
>> Yeah. I I Allah wants to know what does
Afghanistan have in terms of natural
resources in terms of raw materials. So
I can answer this question.
>> Um so in the north there's actually oil
uh not a lot but a decent amount worth
having. Uh in the east in particular
there's rare earth minerals and there's
um there's there's there's gemstones,
there's rubies as you and I both
>> lots of rubies. Yes.
>> Lots of rubies. Um and um and that's
that's basically it, right? I think um
for a long during during the first
Taliban period from 96 to01, it the they
were so poor that their number one
official export was pomegranates.
Um
>> oh my god.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh my god. Pomegranates. Uh you're right
about all the other stuff. They have $23
trillion worth of rare earth metals. And
we learned that just as as US forces
were pulling out and Chinese miners were
moving in.
>> Um,
>> and they're known for their rubies.
Their rubies are, you know, some of the
best in the world. It's it's pretty
impressive. But at the very least, we
should have an embassy open there, even
if it's just two or three people. And we
should be carrying out diplomacy
>> constantly. Yeah. Not to mention, we
still don't we still have some Americans
who got trapped there and who and I mean
they have no consular representation.
>> That's right. What are you gonna do?
>> We abandoned them.
>> Yes, we did.
>> I mean, I don't understand why why why
President Trump hasn't restored those
relationships.
>> I agree with you.
>> Should do it. All right, guys. Thank you
so much for joining us. Uh always
appreciated. We will be back tomorrow uh
at five o'clock Eastern time. Uh we are
here Monday through Friday. You're
watching Drogram with Ted Roll and John
Kuryaku. Please like, follow, and share
the show. Um and we will see you
tomorrow at 5. Bye.
>> Bye everybody.